hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so in this session we are going
to talk about a challenging problem
which uh you might come across uh when
you are trying to test your PDF
documents and you are trying to use the
PDF scan in tosa so the problem here or
maybe the challenge here is uh you need
to count the number of pages in your PDF
document right so you need to verify
whether the PDF uh has got this many
number of pages now the challenge here
is if your PDF document doesn't have any
particular element which tells you the
page number then it will be difficult to
count the number of P pages okay so I
have opened a a sample PDF document and
here you can see um there are no page
numbers mentioned here right so if I go
till down it uh shows me around 57 pages
are there right and that uh you can
count through the PDF uh application but
the actual PDF doesn't have any header
or footer mentioning the page numbers
right so here we need to count the
number number of pages uh which is
57 um and then maybe we can verify that
or buffer that um and that's our
requirement so let's go to tosa and
let's see um what is the actual solution
here right so coming back to a tosa
workspace the first step is to scan the
particular PDF right so we'll go to
modules we'll choose scan and then
choose the PDF option here and then in
here in the PDF scan we are going to
select that particular PDF document
right so I'll select that and click on
open it will open the document in the
PDF scan now here the next step is to
create a particular text area control
okay so we are going to choose the
control Type S text we are going to
select any particular area in the page
okay doesn't matter which area you scan
I just want to create control okay so
here the control has been created and
then I'm just going to save
this then uh we'll close this and we are
going to rename this to sample
PDF and then let's look at the sample
PDF so here you can see uh this is the
text area control and also a div element
has been created now if you don't see
this div element M then just select the
module and press F12 which is the
function F12 key in your keyboard and
then this St element will be created
okay once that's created um go to the
properties for the St element here you
can see the page value is one so we are
going to change this to asri okay which
is a regular expression value for this
particular
property and then we'll close this then
we will go to the test cases section
we'll create a new test case folder
called
PDF and here we will create a test case
to count PDF
pages okay and then uh we are going to
add that particular module
here now uh the first step is to provide
the target PDF path so we'll go to our
PDF document will copy the path here and
paste it
here okay and then um in this particular
Dev elment we are going to choose the
action mode buffer and we are going to
provide a buffer name okay and that's
page
count so this buffer will contain the
number of pages uh for this particular
PDF
document and then in PDF Area 1 we are
going to where verify whether it
satisfies the condition of value um ASC
which is again a regular expression
which means there is no specific uh text
which we want to verify for this PDF
area we are verifying that it is any
particular text uh it doesn't matter we
want to get the count of the pages in
The PDF document okay so what it will do
is it will go through each page uh it
will try to uh get that PDF area with
this particular value which is um Astic
which is a regular expression no
particular text so it can go through all
the pages and then uh subsequently we
can also store uh the page count in the
buffer value okay so now let's see
whether it's working or not so let's
change the work state to completed here
and then let's go ahead and run this in
scratchbook now it might take some time
depending on the number of pages in your
PDF document right uh but once you get
the success message if we go into the
scratchbook logs so here you will see in
the results uh it is storing the page
count so first is set to one similarly
it will go through all the pages and you
will get the final value in your buffer
page count which is 57
right um and then you will see
verification was also successful here
right because it is trying to verify
this particular expression which will
always be true okay uh we can also
verify this uh in our buffer viewer so
we can go to tools buffer viewer and
here uh we can search for pH
count okay so you will see the buffer
value is 57 so this is one way of
finding the number of pages in your PDF
document you can either buffer it and
then you can also verify it whether it
matches your actual number of pages
which was the requirement now the other
way around to do this is if you have got
a PDF document where your header or phot
contains that particular page number for
each page in your PDF document you can
just scan that particular control okay
and then uh you can buffer that
particular value when you are going
through each page so you can mark it as
a repetitive area in your PDF scan
document and then uh you can run that
and that will provide you um the number
of pages in your PDF document so these
are two ways through which you can solve
this particular problem where you have
to verify the number of pages uh in your
PDF
documents that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next video